<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Matt Girdler</title><link>https://www.matthewgirdler.com/</link><description>Recent content on Matt Girdler</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 12:23:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.matthewgirdler.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>2024 in Review</title><link>https://www.matthewgirdler.com/blogs/2024-in-review/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 12:23:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.matthewgirdler.com/blogs/2024-in-review/</guid><description>&lt;p>Another year in the tank - I&amp;rsquo;ll keep the post fairly short this time. It was a productive year at work, helping Met Office to realise some of their socio-economic benefits by publishing multiple products to open data initiatives. A two-year rolling archive of global deterministic atmospheric forecast data can be found on ASDI, alongside a few other Met Office datasets we&amp;rsquo;ve made available this year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://registry.opendata.aws/met-office-global-deterministic/">https://registry.opendata.aws/met-office-global-deterministic/&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We also released the first Met Office products on the Snowflake Marketplace. &lt;a href="https://app.snowflake.com/marketplace/listing/GZTDZJKVBD/met-office-postcode-sector-weather-forecasts-free">https://app.snowflake.com/marketplace/listing/GZTDZJKVBD/met-office-postcode-sector-weather-forecasts-free&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Playing Against the Elements: Analysing Rain and its Effects on Football</title><link>https://www.matthewgirdler.com/blogs/playing-against-the-elements/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 17:31:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.matthewgirdler.com/blogs/playing-against-the-elements/</guid><description>&lt;p>One of the most powerful aspects of data science is its ability to
quantify real world phenomena. To use a popular example in the realm of
football, fans have always recognised that some chances are of a higher
quality than others - a six-yard tap-in is clearly more likely to result
in a goal than a speculative shot from outside of the box - but the advent of expected goals (xG)
and other metrics has changed the way we analyse and understand the
game.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2023 in Review</title><link>https://www.matthewgirdler.com/blogs/2023-in-review/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 15:31:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.matthewgirdler.com/blogs/2023-in-review/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="highs">Highs&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>2023 was a hectic year, to say the least. The biggest achievement was finally moving home in April after having multiple buyers pull out at the last minute. In the end, we opted for a part exchange on a new build which meant we didn&amp;rsquo;t have to worry about estate agent fees and took away a lot of stress that we had been experiencing up to that point. We&amp;rsquo;ve been in the house almost a year now and there&amp;rsquo;s still plenty to do, but we&amp;rsquo;re much happier in the new spot.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2022 in Review</title><link>https://www.matthewgirdler.com/blogs/2022-in-review/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 15:31:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.matthewgirdler.com/blogs/2022-in-review/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="fun-stuff">Fun Stuff&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>My daughter was born in late 2021, so 2022 for me consisted of many great memories. In June we enjoyed our first holiday as a family in Spain which, despite a four hour delayed flight on departure, was a great time and also marked our first trip abroad since COVID. Fortunately, the compensation for the delayed flights paid for a holiday to Menorca in September. Both trips provided some much needed rest and relaxation - albeit less than when it was just me and my wife!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>